	var quizArray = [{
		"id":"0",
		"question":"Flashfloods are floods that happen ___________.",
		"choice1":"Very quickly",
		"choice2":"Only in comic books",
		"choice3":"When lightning hits the floodwater",
		"choice4":"Over thousands of years",
		"correct":"Very quickly"
	},
	{
		"id":"1",
		"question":"Which of the following is NOT considered a natural disaster?",
		"choice1":"Volcano",
		"choice2":"Earthquake",
		"choice3":"Hurricane",
		"choice4":"All of the above are natural disaster",
		"correct":"All of the above are natural disaster"
	},
	{
		"id":"2",
		"question":"Name an item that your family should have in their disaster supply kit in case of an emergency.",
		"choice1":" Tap shoes",
		"choice2":"Bottled water",
		"choice3":"T.V",
		"choice4":"All of the above",
		"correct":"Bottled water"
	},
	{
		"id":"3",
		"question":"A Volcano is classified as dormant, extinct or ____________.",
		"choice1":"Active",
		"choice2":"Friendly",
		"choice3":"Angry",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Active"
	},
	{
		"id":"4",
		"question":" If you were skiing in Chamonix and you sneezed, what could you possibly cause?",
		"choice1":"An avalanche",
		"choice2":"A mudslide",
		"choice3":"A tidalwave",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"An avalanche"
	},
	{
		"id":"5",
		"question":"Is it possible for lightning to strike the same place twice?",
		"choice1":"Yes",
		"choice2":"No",
		"choice3":" Only if it happens to two different people",
		"choice4":" Only if the lightning strikes on a leap year",
		"correct":"Yes"
	},
	{
		"id":"6",
		"question":"Which natural disaster is the most common in the United States and Australia?",
		"choice1":"Tsunami",
		"choice2":" Flooding",
		"choice3":"Tornad",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":" Flooding"
	},
	{
		"id":"7",
		"question":"Name the natural disaster that is considered the most violent?",
		"choice1":"Flood",
		"choice2":"Rainbow",
		"choice3":"Volcano",
		"choice4":"Tornado",
		"correct":"Tornado"
	},
	{
		"id":"8",
		"question":"Tornadoes come in all sizes but usually come in the shape of a ____________.",
		"choice1":"Hexagon",
		"choice2":"Funnel",
		"choice3":"Heart",
		"choice4":"Diamond",
		"correct":"Funnel"
	},
	{
		"id":"9",
		"question":"Which of the following should NOT be included in your flood kit?",
		"choice1":"A torch (flashlight) with spare batteries",
		"choice2":"A wind-up or battery radio",
		"choice3":"Bottle water and non-perishable foods",
		"choice4":"All of the above should be included in your kit",
		"correct":"All of the above should be included in your kit"
	},
	{
		"id":"10",
		"question":"A tornado originates from a ____________.",
		"choice1":"Wildfire",
		"choice2":"Thunderstorm",
		"choice3":"Sun shower",
		"choice4":" All of the above",
		"correct":"Thunderstorm"
	},
	{
		"id":"11",
		"question":"Hurricanes rotate around a/an ________________, which is also something humans have.",
		"choice1":"Eye",
		"choice2":"Nose",
		"choice3":"Mouth",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Eye"
	},
	{
		"id":"12",
		"question":"Which natural disaster CANNOT be predicted?",
		"choice1":"Earthquake",
		"choice2":"Bizzard",
		"choice3":"Typhoon",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Earthquake"
	},
	{
		"id":"13",
		"question":"Who are Hurricane Hunters? ",
		"choice1":"Hurricanes that hunt for other natural disasters to team up with",
		"choice2":"People who fight off hurricanes with long swords",
		"choice3":" People who measure temperature, wind speed and direction inside a hurricane",
		"choice4":"There is no such thing as Hurricane Hunter",
		"correct":"People who measure temperature, wind speed and direction inside a hurricane"
	},
	{
		"id":"14",
		"question":"What is the difference between hurricanes and typhoons?",
		"choice1":"Geography",
		"choice2":"Color",
		"choice3":"Shape",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Geography"
	},
	{
		"id":"15",
		"question":"Hurricanes are classified with the Saffir-Simpson Scale in how many categories?",
		"choice1":"3",
		"choice2":"10",
		"choice3":"5",
		"choice4":"Hurricanes aren't put into categories",
		"correct":"5"
	},
	{
		"id":"16",
		"question":"What are the heavy snows and strong winds that produce a blinding snow?",
		"choice1":"The Saffir-Simpson Scale",
		"choice2":" Bizzards",
		"choice3":"Sunny skies",
		"choice4":"The outer bands",
		"correct":"Bizzards"
	},
	{
		"id":"17",
		"question":"If you are indoors during an earthquake, stay away from ____________.",
		"choice1":"Glass",
		"choice2":"Windows",
		"choice3":"Anything that can fall (like a cabinet or a bookcase)",
		"choice4":" All of the above",
		"correct":" All of the above"
	},
	{
		"id":"18",
		"question":"Which natural disaster can create the faster winds on Earth? (The faster wind speed ever recorded was 318 mph (509 km/h) and struck Oklahoma City!)",
		"choice1":"Snow Storms",
		"choice2":"Tornadoes",
		"choice3":"Wildfires",
		"choice4":" None of the above",
		"correct":"Tornadoes"
	},
	{
		"id":"19",
		"question":"Which state in North America is at the greatest risk of a tsunami?",
		"choice1":"Ohio",
		"choice2":"Colorado",
		"choice3":"Arizona",
		"choice4":"Hawaii",
		"correct":"Hawaii"
	},
	{
		"id":"20",
		"question":"Heavy rains, rivers overflowing, and leaves/dams breaking can all cause which disaster?",
		"choice1":"Earthquake",
		"choice2":"Tornadoes",
		"choice3":"Floods",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Floods"
	},
	{
		"id":"21",
		"question":" Name the severe storms that form in the Western Pacific Ocean. ",
		"choice1":"Tornadoes",
		"choice2":" Cyclones",
		"choice3":"Typhoons",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Tornadoes"
	},
	{
		"id":"22",
		"question":"Hurricanes rotate in which direction?",
		"choice1":"Counter-clockwise",
		"choice2":"Vertical",
		"choice3":"Clockwise",
		"choice4":"Hurricanes don't rotate",
		"correct":"Clockwise"
	},
	{
		"id":"23",
		"question":"The strongest earthquake ever recorded measured a 9.5 on the Richter scale and took place in which country?",
		"choice1":" Albania",
		"choice2":" Ukraine",
		"choice3":"Chile",
		"choice4":"Monaco",
		"correct":"Albania"
	},
	{
		"id":"24",
		"question":"One of the world's worst-ever volcanic eruptions took place 74,000 years ago on an island in which Asian country?",
		"choice1":" Indonesia",
		"choice2":" Iran",
		"choice3":"Japan",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Japan"
	},
	{
		"id":"25",
		"question":"What should you do if you are stuck out doors during a tornado?",
		"choice1":"Lie flat in a ditch or ravine",
		"choice2":"Lie face down and cover your head with your hands",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"None of the above"
	},
	{
		"id":"26",
		"question":"Undersea earthquakes can cause a __________, like the one in Ao Nang, Thailand, by the 2004 Indian Ocean Earthquake - the second largest ever recorded!",
		"choice1":"Epidemic",
		"choice2":"Wildfire",
		"choice3":"Tsunami",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Epidemic"
	},
	{
		"id":"27",
		"question":"Which hurricane was one of the five deadliest and holds the record for being the most destructive storm in terms of economic losses in the history of the United States?",
		"choice1":"Katrina",
		"choice2":"Andrew",
		"choice3":"Alexandria",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Katrina"
	},
	{
		"id":"28",
		"question":"The intensity of an earthquake can be measured using the ________.",
		"choice1":"Richter scale",
		"choice2":"Guttman scale",
		"choice3":"Bathroom scale",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Guttman scale"
	},
	{
		"id":"29",
		"question":"Both lightning and droughts can cause which of the following disasters?",
		"choice1":"Hurricanes",
		"choice2":"Wildfires",
		"choice3":"Avalanches",
		"choice4":"All of the above",
		"correct":"Avalanches"
	},
	{
		"id":"30",
		"question":"Most _______ happen within the Pacific Ocean's Ring of Fire",
		"choice1":"Tornadoes",
		"choice2":"Avalanches",
		"choice3":"Tsunamis",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"None of the above"
	},
	{
		"id":"31",
		"question":"Tornado Alley is a region of land known for the most powerful and destructive tornadoes and is located in what country?.",
		"choice1":"Jordan",
		"choice2":"New Zealand",
		"choice3":"Rwanda",
		"choice4":"The United States",
		"correct":"Jordan"
	},
	{
		"id":"32",
		"question":"Which of the following is not a good place to seek shelter during an earthquake? ",
		"choice1":"under a counter ",
		"choice2":"under a heavy-framed entry way ",
		"choice3":"under a doorway with an attached door ",
		"choice4":"under a sturdy piece of furniture ",
		"correct":"under a doorway with an attached door "
	},
	{
		"id":"33",
		"question":"under a doorway with an attached door ",
		"choice1":"Immediately try to clean it up ",
		"choice2":"Take immediate action to prevent further injuries or damage ",
		"choice3":"Evacuate the building immediately and leave the premises ",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Take immediate action to prevent further injuries or damage "
	},
	{
		"id":"34",
		"question":"What is the first step in knowing what to do in an emergency? ",
		"choice1":"Talking with co-workers about past emergencies ",
		"choice2":"Learning first aid and CPR procedures ",
		"choice3":"Understanding your company’s emergency preparedness program ",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Understanding your company’s emergency preparedness program "
	},
	{
		"id":"35",
		"question":"What is NOT one of the four steps you can take to help your family be prepared for emergencies?",
		"choice1":"Eat your vegetables",
		"choice2":"Get a kit ",
		"choice3":"Be Informed ",
		"choice4":"Get Involved ",
		"correct":"Eat your vegetables "
	},
	{
		"id":"36",
		"question":"What should a Family Communications Plan include? ",
		"choice1":"Information about how we would get in touch with each other during an emergency ",
		"choice2":"Where we would meet",
		"choice3":"How we would remain in contact ",
		"choice4":"All of the above",
		"correct":"All of the above"
	},
	{
		"id":"37",
		"question":"How much water should you have in your Ready Kit? ",
		"choice1":"One small water bottle for each person ",
		"choice2":"One gallon for the whole family ",
		"choice3":"One gallon of water per person per day ",
		"choice4":"One gallon of water for the family per day",
		"correct":"One gallon of water per person per day"
	},
	{
		"id":"38",
		"question":"Which of the following is NOT an important part of a Kid’s Emergency Supply Kit?",
		"choice1":"Flashlight ",
		"choice2":"Batteries ",
		"choice3":"Water",
		"choice4":"Video Games",
		"correct":"Video Games"
	},
	{
		"id":"39",
		"question":"How quickly can a fire spread through a house?",
		"choice1":"10 minutes ",
		"choice2":"As little as five minutes ",
		"choice3":"30 minutes ",
		"choice4":"45 minutes",
		"correct":"As little as five minutes"
	},
	{
		"id":"40",
		"question":"In an emergency, what number should you dial to contact the police and fire department?",
		"choice1":"911 ",
		"choice2":"111 ",
		"choice3":"711 ",
		"choice4":"311",
		"correct":"911 "
	},
	{
		"id":"41",
		"question":"In an emergency, what should you have available to hear news and official reports about what is occurring? ",
		"choice1":"A hand-crank/battery-powered radio",
		"choice2":"A CD player",
		"choice3":"A board game",
		"choice4":"DVD player",
		"correct":"A hand-crank/battery-powered radio"
	},
	{
		"id":"42",
		"question":"If local authorities told me to evacuate, I would: ",
		"choice1":"Refuse to leave. Most ‘emergencies’ don’t turn out to be a big deal.",
		"choice2":"Wait to see if the situation worsened, then decide. ",
		"choice3":"Follow the advice of local responders to ensure my safety and theirs. ",
		"choice4":"Call my ombudsman and see what she thinks I should do. ",
		"correct":"Follow the advice of local responders to ensure my safety and theirs."
	},
	{
		"id":"43",
		"question":"Our emergency supply kit has enough materials to sustain myself and my family: ",
		"choice1":"For at least four hours",
		"choice2":"Through the night",
		"choice3":"Until we get to a shelter",
		"choice4":"For at least three days",
		"correct":"For at least three days"
	},
	{
		"id":"44",
		"question":"In terms of water, our emergency supply kit has:",
		"choice1":"A small bottle for each member of the family",
		"choice2":"A gallon a day for each family member for three days",
		"choice3":"One gallon for the family to share",
		"choice4":"More water for the adults than the kids",
		"correct":"A gallon a day for each family member for three days"
	},
	{
		"id":"45",
		"question":"What best describes an Earthquake?",
		"choice1":"Sudden movement along the earth's surface",
		"choice2":"Huge collision of the earth's plates",
		"choice3":"Violent shaking or motion of the earth's surface",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Violent shaking or motion of the earth's surface"
	},
	{
		"id":"46",
		"question":"What does tsunami literally mean?",
		"choice1":"Harbour wave",
		"choice2":"Huge wave",
		"choice3":"Series of waves",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Harbour wave"
	},
	{
		"id":"47",
		"question":"What is a Flood?",
		"choice1":"The building up of large quantities of water",
		"choice2":"Something similar to a boat wreck",
		"choice3":"The blockage of a water channel",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"The building up of large quantities of water"
	},
	{
		"id":"48",
		"question":"What best describes a Landslide?",
		"choice1":"Descending movement of soil, plant debris and rocks down a slope",
		"choice2":"Sudden movement of soil down a slope",
		"choice3":"Slow movement of soil following heavy rain",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Descending movement of soil, plant debris and rocks down a slope"
	},
	{
		"id":"49",
		"question":"What best describe a hurricane?",
		"choice1":"Strong winds blowing from a sea towards land",
		"choice2":"Strong winds that start over the sea, rotating in big whirling circles",
		"choice3":"Strong winds that cause many trees to crack and fall down",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Strong winds that start over the sea, rotating in big whirling circles"
	},
	{
		"id":"50",
		"question":"What best describe a volcanic eruption?",
		"choice1":"Vertical explosion of gas and ash",
		"choice2":"Explosion or emission of lava, ashes, and toxic gases from deep inside the earth propelled through volcanoes",
		"choice3":"Explosion of fire and magma registered on a Saffir Simpson Scale",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Explosion or emission of lava, ashes, and toxic gases from deep inside the earth propelled through volcanoes"
	},
	{
		"id":"51",
		"question":"Why do earthquakes occur?",
		"choice1":"Because of earth plates moving suddenly",
		"choice2":"Because of two plates knocking together",
		"choice3":"Because of magma moving and the plates sliding in an irregular manner",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Because of earth plates moving suddenly"
	},
	{
		"id":"52",
		"question":"Why do tsunamis occur?l",
		"choice1":"Because of the ocean floor moving, induced by an earthquake and producing gigantic waves",
		"choice2":"Because of ocean water being sucked and, in response, releasing gigantic waves",
		"choice3":"Because of a hurricane, producing strong winds that blow the ocean water into gigantic waves",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Because of the ocean floor moving, induced by an earthquake and producing gigantic waves"
	},
	{
		"id":"53",
		"question":"Why do flooding occur?",
		"choice1":"Because of a lot of water accumulating in a certain place for a long time",
		"choice2":"Usually because of a water dam breaking",
		"choice3":"Generally because of heavy rains where the soil is unable to absorb all the water",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Generally because of heavy rains where the soil is unable to absorb all the water"
	},
	{
		"id":"54",
		"question":"Why do landslides occur?",
		"choice1":"Because of heavy rainfall, or during an earthquake or volcanic eruption",
		"choice2":"Because of land mismanagement or improper land use",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"55",
		"question":"Why do hurricanes occur?",
		"choice1":"Because of heavy rain",
		"choice2":"Because of seasonal change",
		"choice3":"Because of heavy rain occuring above the equator",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Because of seasonal change"
	},
	{
		"id":"56",
		"question":"Why do volcanoes erupt?",
		"choice1":"Because of pressure of the magma inside the earth becomes so great that the magma is emitted outward",
		"choice2":"Because the temperature deep inside the earth reaches its maximum limit",
		"choice3":"Because molten magma explodes out of volcanoes",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Because of pressure of the magma inside the earth becomes so great that the magma is emitted outward"
	},
	{
		"id":"57",
		"question":"Which of the following should you pay attention to before earthquake?",
		"choice1":"Eruption of a volcano",
		"choice2":"Shaking and tremors",
		"choice3":"Cracked land",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Shaking and tremors"
	},
	{
		"id":"58",
		"question":"Which of the following should you pay attention to before tsunami?",
		"choice1":"A big tidal wave",
		"choice2":"Immediate recession of water away from the shoreline",
		"choice3":"Unusual sounds coming from shore",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Immediate recession of water away from the shoreline"
	},
	{
		"id":"59",
		"question":"Which of the following should you pay attention to before flood?",
		"choice1":"A dam break ",
		"choice2":"Prolonged rainfall over several days",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"60",
		"question":"Which of the following should you pay attention to before landslide?",
		"choice1":"An unusual sound that indicates moving debris",
		"choice2":"The sound of water flowing",
		"choice3":"A loud sound rom the sky, like a thunderstorm",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"An unusual sound that indicates moving debris"
	},
	{
		"id":"61",
		"question":"Which of the following should you pay attention to before hurricane?",
		"choice1":"Frequent strong winds blowing",
		"choice2":"Seasonal change",
		"choice3":"Heavy rainfall",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Seasonal change"
	},
	{
		"id":"62",
		"question":"Which of the following should you pay attention to before volcanic eruption?",
		"choice1":"Frequent ejection of volcanic ash",
		"choice2":"Frequent earthquakes",
		"choice3":"Decreased ambient temperature",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Frequent ejection of volcanic ash"
	},
	{
		"id":"63",
		"question":"What is one of the most important actions to take before an earthquake? ",
		"choice1":"Locate safe spots in each room",
		"choice2":"Move to higher ground",
		"choice3":"Place large items in high places",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Locate safe spots in each room"
	},
	{
		"id":"64",
		"question":"What is one of the most important actions to take before a tsunami?",
		"choice1":"Learn the evacuation route",
		"choice2":"prepare a fibre boat",
		"choice3":"Discuss with household members",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Learn the evacuation route"
	},
	{
		"id":"65",
		"question":"What is one of the most important actions to take before a flood?",
		"choice1":"Prepare an emergency kit",
		"choice2":".Bulk together staple food",
		"choice3":"Make a canoe",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Prepare an emergency kit"
	},
	{
		"id":"66",
		"question":"What is one of the most important actions to take before a landslide?",
		"choice1":"Make a brick barrier in front of the house",
		"choice2":"Prepare sandbags",
		"choice3":"Be alert to changes and patterns in the land",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Be alert to changes and patterns in the land"
	},
	{
		"id":"67",
		"question":"What is one of the most important actions to take before a hurricane?",
		"choice1":"Stay indoors the whole day",
		"choice2":"Select a safe place outdoors",
		"choice3":"Get proper protection for all windows and doors",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Get proper protection for all windows and doors"
	},
	{
		"id":"68",
		"question":"What is one of the most important actions to take before a volcanic eruption?",
		"choice1":"Cover garden with soil",
		"choice2":"Keep goggles and a dust mask handy",
		"choice3":"Read about volcanic eruptions in text books",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Keep goggles and a dust mask handy"
	},
	{
		"id":"69",
		"question":"How do you stay safe during an earthquake?",
		"choice1":"If inside when the shaking starts, move no more than a few steps, drop to the ground, cover and hold on",
		"choice2":"If outside, find a clear spot and drop to the ground ",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"70",
		"question":"How do you stay safe during a tsunami?",
		"choice1":"Evacuate immediately",
		"choice2":"Listen to the news on the radio ",
		"choice3":"Drop to the ground, cover and hold on",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Evacuate immediately"
	},
	{
		"id":"71",
		"question":"How do you stay safe during a flood?",
		"choice1":"Put on your swimming suit",
		"choice2":"Climb to the higher ground",
		"choice3":"Ask a member from the rescue team to stay with you",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Climb to the higher ground"
	},
	{
		"id":"72",
		"question":"How do you stay safe during a landslide",
		"choice1":"Go outside to observe the landslide",
		"choice2":"Get out of the landslides path",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"73",
		"question":"How do you stay safe during a hurricane?",
		"choice1":"Get on a boat and head far away from shore",
		"choice2":"Stay inside a safe home for as long as the hurricane prevails",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"74",
		"question":"How do you stay safe during a volcanic eruption?",
		"choice1":"Evacuate to lower ground ",
		"choice2":"Evacuate or take shelter",
		"choice3":"Wear goggles and a dust mask",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Evacuate or take shelter"
	},
	{
		"id":"75",
		"question":"The first action I will take after an earthquake is...",
		"choice1":"Expect after-shocks",
		"choice2":"Beware of fires",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"76",
		"question":"The first action I will take after a tsunami is...",
		"choice1":"Stay away from debris in the water",
		"choice2":"Seek food from anywhere",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"77",
		"question":"The first action I will take after a flood is...",
		"choice1":"Prepare my floating rubber boat",
		"choice2":"Help myself then others",
		"choice3":"Stay away from the flooded house",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Help myself then others"
	},
	{
		"id":"78",
		"question":"The first action I will take after a landslide is...",
		"choice1":"Stay away from the areas of landslide",
		"choice2":"Search around from hazards",
		"choice3":"Collect belongings among the debris",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Stay away from the areas of landslide"
	},
	{
		"id":"79",
		"question":"The first action I will take after a hurricane is...",
		"choice1":"Check for danger inside and outside",
		"choice2":"Mend my damaged house",
		"choice3":"Search for lost belongings",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Check for danger inside and outside"
	},
	{
		"id":"80",
		"question":"The first action I will take after a volcanic eruption is...",
		"choice1":"Stay inside",
		"choice2":"Protect my lungs and eyes from volcanic ash",
		"choice3":"Both A and B",
		"choice4":"None of the above",
		"correct":"Both A and B"
	},
	{
		"id":"81",
		"question":"About how many people died in the December 26, 2004 tsunami?",
		"choice1":"30,000",
		"choice2":"300,000",
		"choice3":"3,000,000",
		"choice4":"30,000,000",
		"correct":"300,000"
	},
	{
		"id":"82",
		"question":"The Great Chilean earthquake of 1960 was the largest earthquake ever recorded. What did it score on the Richter scale?",
		"choice1":"8.9",
		"choice2":"9.5",
		"choice3":"10.1",
		"choice4":"11.0",
		"correct":"9.5"
	},
	{
		"id":"83",
		"question":"A place where an earthquake originates is called the __________.",
		"choice1":"Focus",
		"choice2":"Tsunami",
		"choice3":"Fault Line",
		"choice4":"Epicenter",
		"correct":"Focus"
	},
	{
		"id":"84",
		"question":"Which natural hazard has resulted in the greatest monetary losses in a single event for the period of time listed?",
		"choice1":"earthquake",
		"choice2":"hurricane",
		"choice3":"fire",
		"choice4":"flood",
		"correct":"hurricane"
	},
	{
		"id":"85",
		"question":"The largest wave during a tsunami event is __________________.",
		"choice1":"the first",
		"choice2":"the third",
		"choice3":"the fifth",
		"choice4":"unpredictable, it could be any of them",
		"correct":"unpredictable, it could be any of them"
	},
	{
		"id":"86",
		"question":"The destructive powers of tsunami result mainly from their ___________________.",
		"choice1":"incredible height",
		"choice2":"unpredictablility",
		"choice3":"cold water",
		"choice4":"momentum and long wavelength",
		"correct":"momentum and long wavelength"
	},
	{
		"id":"87",
		"question":"In the open ocean, tsunami can travel ________ miles per hour with periods up to _________ minutes.",
		"choice1":"50; 20",
		"choice2":"50; 60",
		"choice3":"485; 20",
		"choice4":"485; 60",
		"correct":"485; 60"
	},
	{
		"id":"88",
		"choice1":" Which event produces the biggest tsunami?",
		"question":"Earthquake",
		"choice2":"Underwater landslides",
		"choice3":"Hurricanes",
		"choice4":"Impacts of asteroids and comets",
		"correct":"Impacts of asteroids and comets"
	},
	{
		"id":"89",
		"question":"Which law created the first permanent system for disaster relief eliminating the need for congressional action after every disaster?",
		"choice1":"Federal Disaster Relief Act of 1950 ",
		"choice2":"Federal Civil Defense Act of 1950",
		"choice3":"Homeland Security Act of 2002",
		"choice4":"Stafford Act of 1988",
		"correct":"Federal Disaster Relief Act of 1950 "
	},
	{
		"id":"90",
		"question":"In academic terms an event in which a community undergoes severe danger and incurs, or is threatened with, such losses to persons and/or property that the resources available within the community to address the event are exceeded, is defined as",
		"choice1":"an emergency",
		"choice2":"a disaster",
		"choice3":"a mass emergency",
		"choice4":"a catastrophe",
		"correct":"a disaster"
	},
	{
		"id":"91",
		"question":"The last major super-volcano eruption - 75,000 years ago - killed about which % of the world's humans?",
		"choice1":"0%",
		"choice2":"1%",
		"choice3":"5%",
		"choice4":"60%",
		"correct":"60%"
	},
	{
		"id":"92",
		"question":"Which was the deadliest hurricane in US History?",
		"choice1":"Katrina",
		"choice2":"Galveston Hurricane of 1900",
		"choice3":"Andrew",
		"choice4":"Camille",
		"correct":"Galveston Hurricane of 1900"
	},
	{
		"id":"93",
		"question":"Which European city was almost entirely destroyed by a combination earthquake/fire/tsunami in 1755?",
		"choice1":"Lisbon",
		"choice2":"Rome",
		"choice3":"Barcelona",
		"choice4":"Athens",
		"correct":"Lisbon"
	},
	{
		"id":"94",
		"question":"Not counting pandemics, the two deadliest natural disasters on record were both:",
		"choice1":"Floodings of the Yellow River in China",
		"choice2":"Monsoons in India",
		"choice3":"Hurricanes in Bangladesh",
		"choice4":"Earthquakes in Pakistan",
		"correct":"Floodings of the Yellow River in China"
	},
	{
		"id":"95",
		"question":"As the magnitude of natural disasters increases their frequency of occurrence _________.",
		"choice1":"increases",
		"choice2":"decreases",
		"choice3":"remains the same",
		"choice4":"varies over time",
		"correct":"decreases"
	},
	{
		"id":"96",
		"question":"Powerful tsunami are most frequently produced by _________.",
		"choice1":"volcanoes",
		"choice2":"underwater landslides",
		"choice3":"Earthquakes",
		"choice4":"impacts of asteroids",
		"correct":"Earthquakes"
	},
	{
		"id":"97",
		"question":" Which law instituted FEMA’s Individual and Family Grant (IFG) program, which provided 75 percent of the funding for State-administered programs providing cash help for furniture, clothes, and essential needs.",
		"choice1":"Disaster Relief Act of 1950",
		"choice2":"Disaster Relief Act of 1974",
		"choice3":"Stafford Act of 1988",
		"choice4":"Disaster Mitigation Act of 2000",
		"correct":"Disaster Relief Act of 1974"
	},
	{
		"id":"98",
		"question":"The Federal-State cost share in paying for disaster relief under a major disaster declaration is usually done on a",
		"choice1":"Federal covers 30%, states cover 70% basis",
		"choice2":"Federal covers 75%, states cover 25% basis",
		"choice3":"Federal covers 25%, states cover 75% basis",
		"choice4":"Federal covers 50%, states cover 50% basis",
		"correct":"Federal covers 75%, states cover 25% basis"
	},
	{
		"id":"99",
		"question":"What causes flood?",
		"choice1":"Cutting of trees",
		"choice2":"Unproper throwing of garbages",
		"choice3":"A and B",
		"choice4":" None of the above",
		"correct":"A and B"

	
	}];